thehoroscope.co 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy!

We take and respect your privacy seriously.

The purpose of this policy is to explain to you how we control, process, handle and protect your personal information while browsing or using this website, including your rights under current laws and regulations. If you do not agree to the following policy you may wish to cease viewing / using this Website.

For our European users, please note that this Privacy Policy is GDPR compliant.

We tried to avoid too much legalese and our goal is for this Privacy Policy to be transparent and clear to you. Should you have any questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please do not hesitate to contact us following the contact details provided further down. 

#### Processing of your personal data

The purposes for collecting information about you are:

  * To determine what you may like or find interesting, so we can provide you with targeted information and advertising on our Website;
  * Whenever the case, to be able to reply to you when you contact us through the contact form available on the Website.

Under the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) we control and / or process any personal information about you electronically using the lawful basis of consent.

If, as determined by us, the lawful basis upon which we process your personal information changes, we will notify you about the change and any new lawful basis to be used if required. We shall stop processing your personal information if the lawful basis used is no longer relevant. 

#### Types of Data Collected

You actively send information to us when you use this Website or subscribe to our newsletter, post opinions, comments, respond to us or otherwise contact us.

With your direct consent the data we may collect is:

  * Your Name;
  * Email address;
  * Mailing address;
  * Phone number;
  * Any other details you may voluntarily send when contacting us.

We automatically track information through Google Analytics from your device or web browser when you interact with the Website. In this respect the data we may collect includes:

  * Internet domain from which you access this Website;
  * IP address;
  * Browser type and operating system;
  * Data and hour when you accessed the Website;
  * Pages that were visited;
  * The referral link that redirected to us;
  * Any other navigational and stat data we consider important.

This information is used to facilitate collection of data concerning your interaction with the Website and to otherwise personalize, improve and continue to operate the Website.

#### Your individual rights

Under the GDPR your rights are as follows. You can read more about [your rights in details here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/);

  * the right to be informed;
  * the right of access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure;
  * the right to restrict processing;
  * the right to data portability;
  * the right to object; and
  * the right not to be subject to automated decision-making including profiling.

We handle subject access requests in accordance with the GDPR.

#### Data security and protection

We ensure the security of any personal information we hold by using secure data storage technologies and precise procedures in how we store, access and manage that information (e.g. we have installed SSL certificate for connection encryption). 

#### Data retention period

We usually delete the emails we receive through the Website’s contact form within 30 days of receipt. The data we collect through Google Analytics was set up to be deleted after 14 months.

In regard to the cookies we use, you can delete those at any time, through your browser settings.

We will continue to process your information under this basis until you withdraw consent or it is determined your consent no longer exists.  

#### Information related to Advertising

Our Website may contain adverts, sponsored and affiliate links on some pages. These are typically served through our advertising partners. At the moment we are only using Google AdSense. We only use trusted advertising partners who each have high standards of user privacy and security.

These advertisements are sometimes targeted and served to particular users and may come from third party companies called "ad networks." Ad networks include third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors and research firms. We may engage with ad networks that are members or organizations or programs that manage the advertising privacy choices these ad networks offer consumers.

However, we do not control the actual adverts seen / displayed by our advertising partners. Our ad partners may collect data and use cookies for ad personalisation and measurement. Where ad preferences are requested as 'non-personalised' cookies may still be used for frequency capping, aggregated ad reporting and to combat fraud and abuse. To opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

The Website does not have any control or access over the placement of cookies or other tracking mechanisms that any third party may use or the information any third party may collect. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these ad networks and other parties.

Please note that for EEA users, we have opted for displaying non-personalised Google AdSense ads.

You acknowledge that third parties may use cookies which have been placed on your computer to gather information about you and understand the types of pages visited by you and content that you view on our Website.

We use advertising partners in these ways to help generate an income from the website, which allows us to continue our work and provide you with the best overall experience and valued information. 

#### Your contact with other third parties

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, including but not limited to any third party websites, services and applications, such as Facebook that you elect to access through the Service. While we attempt to facilitate access only to those third party Websites or Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of those third party Websites or Services.

The Website does not make any representations or warranties with respect to any content or privacy practices, or otherwise with respect to such third parties or any items or services that may be obtained from such third parties, and you agree that the Website will have no liability with respect to any loss or damage of any kind incurred as a result of any dealings between you and any third party, or as a result of the presence of such third parties on the Website.

Your dealings with advertisers or other third parties found on or accessible through the Website are solely between you and the third party and you make them solely at your own risk.

We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any third party Websites or Services you access. 

#### Disclosure of Data

We keep the data we collect confidential and we generally do not disclose it, with the exception of the following:

  * Our external suppliers, such as Google Analytics and Google AdSense, may have access to part of your data in order to help us provide the service through this Website (and not for their own purposes). They access and use such data subject to our instructions, and under confidentiality and security obligations;
  * If we ever sell this Website or any parts of our business, we may disclose the data that we collect to a (prospective) buyer by the condition that such third party agrees to comply to the Privacy Policy;
  * We may also share the data we collect about you to respond to law enforcement requests, court orders or other legal process or if we believe that such disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent or respond to illegal activities, fraud, physical threats to you or others required by any applicable law or regulation.
  * We do not directly provide the data we collect about you to any advertising customers. However, they may find it or use it indirectly. We freely use and disclose data in anonymous form, for instance, in statistics or reports to our advertising customers.

Take note that posting any information in any area of our Website that is generally accessible to users (such as comments area, but not limited to) will make you the only responsible for it and that will be available to the public. 

#### Cookie Policy

We use cookies on this website to provide you with a better user experience. We do this by placing a small text file on your device / computer hard drive to track how you use the website, to record or log whether you have seen particular messages that we display, to display relevant adverts or content, refer you to a third-party website.

We make available a cookie control system which allows you to accept or deny the use of the Google Analytics cookies we use. Some cookies will be saved for specific time periods, where others may last indefinitely. Your web browser should provide you with the controls to manage and delete cookies from your device, so please see your web browser options.

[Please see our Cookie Policy](https://www.thehoroscope.co/cookie-policy.php) for more detail about the information we may collect automatically and your choices. 

#### What information of mine can I access?

As the Website does not have registered users, unregistered users can access and delete cookies through their web browser settings.

Alternatively, we also make available a cookie control system which allows you to accept or deny the use of the Google Analytics cookies we use. [You can find it HERE](https://www.thehoroscope.co/cookie-policy.php). 

#### Contact Information

If you have any questions or queries or concerns with respect to this Privacy Policy or the Website you may contact a representative of Thehoroscope.co by email at privacy@thehoroscope.co 

#### Updates of the Privacy Policy

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time and without prior notice to you. If we make changes in the way we collect or use data, we will notify you by posting an announcement in this Privacy Policy and, in certain circumstances, seeking your consent. 

Version 1.0 – Last updated: 25 May 2018
